http://www.carmelites.org.au/privacy-policies

Menu
HomeLatest NewsAbout the Carmelites>open
About UsCarmelite RuleCarmelite CharismMary and ElijahCarmelite FiguresLay CarmelitesNational Shrine of Our Lady of Mount CarmelCarmelite ConstitutionsHistory of the ProvinceHistory of the Carmelite OrderOur Work>open
ParishesEducationSpirituality CentresCarmelite LibraryJustice, Peace & Integrity of CreationJoining Us>open
The Carmelite StoryDiscerning my personal VocationPrayers for DiscernmentFinding DirectionMaking a DecisionPrayers for GuidanceLay CarmelitesDownload Our BrochureTimor-Leste Mission>open
Mission OverviewZumalaiDiliLay Carmelites>open
Who are the Lay Carmelites?Lay Carmelite Rule & StatutesPrayer and Reflections>open
Advent & ChristmasLectio DivinaThe Brown ScapularCarmelite Web of Prayer for VocationsCarmelite Prayer CardsNovena of PrayerCommunications>open
Carmelite CommunicationsPublicationsCarmelite LinksOther Web SitesCarmelite CalendarSupport Our WorkDesktop WallpaperCalendarContact UsSafeguarding & Professional StandardsCelebrating at Home
Privacy Policy
font size
decrease font size
increase font size
Print
Email
Rate this item
1
2
3
4
5
(0 votes)
PRIVACY STATEMENT
This statement applies to the following entities:
The Carmelite Fathers Incorporated (Vic.) ABN 98 004 769 528;
Carmelite Memorial Library of Spirituality and Mariology ABN 84 838 823 572;
The Carmelite Centre ABN 68 098 608 698; and
The Carmelites - Australia and Timor-Leste Ltd, ABN 72 626 911 377,
each of 75 Wright St, Middle Park, Victoria 3206 (together referred to in this document as the “Carmelite Fathers”, “we”, “us” and “our”).
The Carmelite Fathers are committed to protecting the privacy of personal information which we collect and with complying with applicable obligations under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (the “Act”). Personal information includes information or an opinion which identifies a person.
The Carmelite Fathers collect personal information in three principle ways:
Our general fundraising and community engagement activities;
The Carmelite Centre; and
The Carmelite Library.
PRIVACY COLLECTION NOTICE: GENERAL (Australian Privacy Principle 5.2)
This collection notice relates to personal information collected by the Carmelite Fathers in connection with its general fundraising and community engagement activities.
Who is collecting the information?
The Carmelite Fathers Incorporated (Vic.) ABN 98 004 769 528, Carmelite Memorial Library of Spirituality and Mariology ABN 84 838 823 572, The Carmelite Centre ABN 68 098 608 698 and The Carmelites - Australia and Timor-Leste Ltd, ABN 72 626 911 377 of 75 Wright St, Middle Park, Victoria 3206.
Our contact details are as follows:
Business Manager Tel:  (03) 9699 1922 Email: This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it.
How is the information collected?
We collect personal information from people who wish to donate, volunteer with us, enquire about vocations with us, seek or are undergoing formation with us, or otherwise support the Carmelite Fathers.
Is the collection required under a law or Court order?
No.
What are the purposes of collection?
The purpose of the collection is to process your donation, your application to volunteer with us, you enquiry regarding vocations, your application to undergo formation with us, issue receipts, maintain records and to respond to your feedback or concerns. The purpose includes inviting you to participate in other activities and ministries of the Carmelite Fathers and to find out about other opportunities to support our work or volunteer with us.
What happens if we don’t collect this information?
Without this information we are unable to process your donation, consider your enquiry or application to volunteer or undergo formation with us, or provide you with newsletters or updates regarding our work.
Can you be anonymous?
You can request that we don’t record your name when you donate; however, we still need to confirm your identify before we can accept your donation. We also need to collect sufficient information from our volunteers and applicants for formation to maintain appropriate records and satisfy our safeguarding requirements.
To whom do we share this information?
We share this information with other affiliated Carmelite organisations and service providers, such as information technology or other service providers.
Do we share the information overseas?
Generally no, although on occasion backups of data stored on our cloud servers may be replicated on other servers hosted overseas.
How can I access and seek correction of this information?
Information about how to access and seek correction of personal information we hold about you is contained in our privacy policy.
How can I complain?
Information about how to complain is contained in our privacy policy. You may also direct complaints to the Australian Information Commissioner as www.oaic.gov.au.
PRIVACY COLLECTION NOTICE: THE CARMELITE CENTRE (Australian Privacy Principle 5.2)
This collection notice relates to personal information collected by the Carmelite Fathers in connection with the Carmelite Centre at 214 Richardson Street, Middle Park, Victoria 3206.
Who is collecting the information?
The Carmelite Fathers Incorporated (Vic.) ABN 98 004 769 528, Carmelite Memorial Library of Spirituality and Mariology ABN 84 838 823 572, The Carmelite Centre ABN 68 098 608 698 and The Carmelites - Australia and Timor-Leste Ltd, ABN 72 626 911 377 of 75 Wright St Middle Park VIC 3206.
Our contact details are as follows:
Business Manager Tel:  (03) 9699 1922 Email: This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it.
How is the information collected?
We collect personal information from people who wish to attend lectures, seminars, sessions, Lectio Divina, retreats, and other events organised by the Carmelite Centre.
Is the collection required under a law or Court order?
No.
What are the purposes of collection?
The primary purpose of the collection is to verify your identity, allow us to process your booking, and to provide you with materials about proposed events organised by the Carmelite Centre.
The secondary purpose is to invite you to participate in other activities and ministries of the Carmelite Fathers and to find out about opportunities to support our work or volunteer with us.
What happens if we don’t collect this information?
Without this information we are unable to process your booking or provide you with newsletters or updates regarding proposed events.
Can you be anonymous?
Yes, you are still welcome to visit those public sessions at the Centre which do not require a booking in advance. However, you will not be able to attend our private booked or offsite sessions or receive our periodic communications.
To whom do we share this information?
We share this information with other affiliated Carmelite organisations and service providers, such as information technology or other service providers.
Do we share the information overseas?
Generally no, although on occasion backups of data stored on our cloud servers may be replicated on other servers hosted overseas.
How can I access and seek correction of this information?
Information about how to access and seek correction of personal information we hold about you is contained in our privacy policy.
How can I complain?
Information about how to complain is contained in our privacy policy. You may also direct complaints to the Australian Information Commissioner as www.oaic.gov.au.
PRIVACY COLLECTION NOTICE: THE CARMELITE LIBRARY (Australian Privacy Principle 5.2)
This collection notice relates to personal information collected by the Carmelite Fathers in connection with the Carmelite Library at 214 Richardson Street, Middle Park, Victoria 3206.
Who is collecting the information?
The Carmelite Fathers Incorporated (Vic.) ABN 98 004 769 528, Carmelite Memorial Library of Spirituality and Mariology ABN 84 838 823 572, The Carmelite Centre ABN 68 098 608 698 and The Carmelites - Australia and Timor-Leste Ltd, ABN 72 626 911 377 of 75 Wright St Middle Park VIC 3206.
Our contact details are as follows:
Business Manager Tel:  (03) 9699 1922 Email: This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it.
How is the information collected?
We collect personal information from people who wish to borrow materials from the library, sign-up to our newsletters, subscribe to membership, or be alerted when new collections are available or materials are returned.
Is the collection required under a law or Court order?
No.
What are the purposes of collection?
The primary purpose of the collection is to verify your identity, allow us to maintain a record of borrowed materials, follow up borrowers who have not returned materials, and to manage membership subscriptions (including renewals).
The secondary purpose is to invite you to participate in other activities and ministries of the Carmelite Fathers and to find out about opportunities to support our work or volunteer with us.
What happens if we don’t collect this information?
Without this information we are unable to process borrowing requests or provide you with newsletters or updates regarding when new collections are available or materials are returned.
Can you be anonymous?
Yes, you are still welcome to visit the library and review materials there. However, you will not be able to borrow any materials or receive our periodic communications.
To whom do we share this information?
We share this information with other affiliated Carmelite organisations and service providers, such as information technology or other service providers.
Do we share the information overseas?
Generally no, although on occasion backups of data stored on our cloud servers may be replicated on other servers hosted overseas.
How can I access and seek correction of this information?
Information about how to access and seek correction of personal information we hold about you is contained in our privacy policy.
How can I complain?
Information about how to complain is contained in our privacy policy. You may also direct complaints to the Australian Information Commissioner as www.oaic.gov.au.
PRIVACY POLICY (Australian Privacy Principle 1.3 - 1.6)
Introduction
The Carmelite Fathers Incorporated (Vic.) ABN 98 004 769 528, Carmelite Memorial Library of Spirituality and Mariology ABN 84 838 823 572, The Carmelite Centre ABN 68 098 608 698 and The Carmelites - Australia and Timor-Leste Ltd, ABN 72 626 911 377 of 75 Wright St Middle Park VIC 3206 (together referred to in this document as the “Carmelite Fathers”, “we”, “us” and “our”) respect and uphold your rights under the Australian Privacy Principles contained in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (Privacy Act).
In this policy, personal information and sensitive information have the same meanings as under the Privacy Act.
This policy sets out our commitments to you about personal information and sensitive information we may hold about you.
How do we collect and hold information about you?
We will generally collect information about you (whether personal information or sensitive information) and other information directly from you but also from others who provide the information to us in person, via phone or via our website(s) or social media platforms (including via cookies).
What information about you do we collect and hold?
Personal information
The types of personal information we collect about you will be directly related to the specific purpose for which it has been collected. How much personal information you choose to disclose to us is completely up to you but limited information may mean we are unable to process your request or provide you with the relevant product or service.
The information we collect will include a range of your name, date of birth, email address, phone number(s), street address and banking or payment card information as relevant and are collected when you engage with us, including when you:
make a donation to us;
purchase a product from us or register to attend one of our events;
apply to volunteer with us;
enquire about vocations or apply for, or undergo, formation with us;
make an enquiry, provide feedback or make a complaint to us; or
apply for employment with us.
Sensitive information
We do not generally collect sensitive information unless it is relevant and we have your prior consent. Where sensitive information is disclosed in the course of individual counselling sessions (if applicable), we will seek your express consent regarding how we may use or disclose that information.
Web information
When you visit any of our websites, the relevant site server by automated means (such as cookies) makes a record of the visit and collects the following information:
your server address – to enable us to tailor the website to your interests and requirements;
the date and time of your visit – to enable us to know the website’s busy times;
pages accessed and documents downloaded – to inform us about popular and important documents;
duration of the visit – to tell us how interesting and informative the website is to you;
the type of browser used – for browser specific coding; and
your domain name or IP address, computer operating system, browser type and screen resolution - to enable us to optimise the website for different browsers.
You can change the privacy settings of your browser, in particular, you can refuse all cookies or opt to be notified each time a cookie is sent to your computer.  By blocking or deleting cookies used on our website(s), you may not be able to take full advantage of products or services offered via our website(s).
What will we do with information we hold about you?
Storage and security of information
We will take reasonable steps to protect your information and to protect information from loss, misuse, and unauthorised access, use, modification, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.  This includes complying with the Payment Card Information Data Security Standard, which covers the security of payment card information.
You should keep in mind that the transmission of information over the internet (including by email) is not completely secure or error-free and you should take care in deciding what information you send to us via the internet.
Use and disclosure of information
Personal Information
We will only use and disclose your personal information for the purposes for which you provide it or a related secondary purpose which you would reasonably expect (including as stated in our specific collection statements).  This includes, for example:
providing the products and/or services you have requested from us;
providing you with email newsletters to which you have specifically subscribed;
responding to any enquiries, feedback or complaints made by you; or
assessing any application for employment with us.
We may disclose your personal information to:
other companies or people that we have your consent to share the information with;
other affiliate Carmelite entities; and
contractors and third party service providers that we engage in the ordinary course of our business where necessary to enable us to provide you with products and/or services.
We may disclose your personal information to other companies or people that we have your consent to share the information with, and contractors and third party service providers that we engage in the ordinary course of our business where necessary to enable us to provide you with products and/or services.  We do not, generally, disclose your personal information to recipients outside of Australia.  If we do so, for example, where a cloud service provider creates a backup of our data and stores that backup overseas, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is handled by any overseas recipients in accordance with the Privacy Act and our instructions for the purposes described above.  Any such backups of the data will be held in the United States of America, Singapore or within the European Economic Area. By providing us with your personal information, you consent to this disclosure of your personal information.
We, or third parties engaged to act on our behalf, may contact you from time to time with marketing material about our products or services, where you have consented to this or where we believe you would reasonably expect us to do so. You may opt out of receiving this material at any time by taking the steps in any “unsubscribe” instructions we send to you or by contacting our Privacy Officer.
Sensitive information
We will never disclose your sensitive information unless we have your consent to do so.
Web information
This information will be used only for statistical and administrative purposes.
Retention and destruction of personal and sensitive information
We will destroy or de-identify your personal and sensitive information as soon as practicable once it is no longer needed for the purpose for which it was collected. However, we may be required by law to retain your personal information after your relationship with us has expired.  We will take reasonable steps and use appropriate techniques and processes in destroying information.
Openness
You may request access to information we hold about you by contacting the Privacy Officer - address below. If it is information that you are entitled to access, we will endeavour to provide it to you in a suitable way (e.g. emailing or mail). We may charge you a fee to cover our costs.
You may request us to update or amend information we hold about you; we will either amend the information, or make a record of your request, as appropriate.
Questions and feedback
If you have any questions or feedback about this policy or our commitments to you please contact our Privacy Officer:
Privacy Officer Carmelite Fathers
75 Wright St, Middle Park VIC 3206 Tel:  (03) 9699 1922 Email: This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it.
We commit to respond in a timely manner.
If your feedback is a complaint, we will advise what (if any) action we consider appropriate to take in response or if we do not agree with you, we will provide reasons.  If you remain unsatisfied you can contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (www.oaic.com.au).
This policy is effective from 1 June 2019. We may change this policy from time to time. Although we intend to observe this policy at all times, it is not legally binding on us in any way. From time to time we may regard it as necessary or desirable to act outside the policy.  We may do so, subject only to any other applicable contractual rights you have and any statutory rights you have under the Privacy Act or other applicable legislation.
Tweet
More in this category:
« Welcome
Safeguarding & Professional Standards »
back to top
Calendar
14
Dec
St John of the Cross, Priest and Doctor of the Church
Date
14.12.20
17
Carmelites talk about St Joseph
Rejoice! The Lord is near!
Pope Francis declares Year of St Joseph
Lay Carmelites make final commitment
Subscribe to our eNewsletter
Thank you! Please check your email and confirm the newsletter subscription.
Your subscription was updated
Email *
It seems that you have already subscribed to this list.										Click here to update your profile.
First Name
Last Name
Subscribe
Carmelite Provincial Centre. 75 Wright Street, Middle Park Victoria 3206 Australia.Ph: +61 3 9699 1922 Fax: +61 3 9699 1944 Email: provincialoffice@carmelites.org.au
| Privacy Policy |
/
×
Tweets by carmelitesaet
